This is really profound. I don't think I
have seen anything like this from a
large language model. Okay. So, we have
yet another one trillion parameter open
weight model. This is called ling.
That means we have officially entered
the era of actual large language models.
Now, this one is interesting because of
the company who created this model. More
on them later in the video, but they
claim that it beats both openweight and
proprietary models on a number of key
math and reasoning benchmarks. Look at
this ARGI1 score. Pretty incredible.
Also, it seems to be state-of-the-art or
close to state-of-the-art on a number of
key coding benchmarks. But the thing
that caught my attention was its token
efficiency. If you look on AM 2025, it
achieves state-of-the-art performance
with almost 40% less tokens compared to
Gemini 2.5 Pro, which is pretty
interesting. However, this is a
non-cognitive model or in other words,
it's a non-thinking or non-reasoning
model, which I think makes the results
even more interesting. It's a mixture of
expert with 1 trillion total parameters
per token. It has only 50 billion
parameters activated. That means it's a
sparse mixture of expert with a context
window of 128,000 tokens. But they have
done what they're calling evolutionary
chain of thought with mid-training and
post- trainining which makes it a lot
token efficient compared to some of the
other offerings that we have seen. This
is from a research group called
inclusion AI who are part of ants group
AGI initiative. Ant group is closely
associated with Alibaba and Alibaba has
their Quen series of models which are
pretty incredible openweight model and
now ant group through inclusion AI is
also creating some really strong
openweight models. The model weight are
already available on hugging face and
there are a couple of platforms where
you can test it out. We're going to look
at some of my own tests shortly. These
benchmarks looks very interesting, but
we're going to run some of my own tests.
Before that, I want to look at some of
the architectural details and some
interesting things that they have done
with this model. They recently published
this paper towards greater leverage
scaling laws of efficient mixture of
expert language models. So here they
showed that it's possible to scale these
to large 1 trillion parameter models.
Now in this case they're using about 20
trillion tokens of high quality high
reasoning density. The reasoning comes
from what they are calling evolutionary
chain of thought. So these are the
reasoning traces that were produced for
training of this non-reasoning or
non-cognitive
model. The architecture looks very
similar to DeepSeek in my opinion.
although they don't use some of the
techniques like MLA that were introduced
by them. However, here's the most
interesting bit. So, this was trained
entirely in FP8 mixed precision training
which according to them makes it the
largest scale known foundation model
trained with FP8. Now, DeepSeek R1 was
also trained with FB8, but that's a
relatively smaller model compared to
Linget.
So, I wanted to test some of the claims
to see how good this model is at
training. So, I put it to a number of
different tests. I'm going to show you
some of the results. Now, the model is
available on Zenmucks. If you sign up,
you get $5 worth of tokens or credits.
They have a number of different models.
The model that you want to select is
inclusion AI link oneT
and here you can see the token
efficiency. Now one thing which I think
that they could potentially improve is
that currently the context window is
limited to only 128,000 tokens. It can
generate up to 32,000 tokens which is
the max output. If you want to test the
model just click on chat. Here is the
model that you can select. The pricing
is pretty reasonable even on this
platform. I'm not affiliated with it at
all, but let's test it out. Okay, so
we're going to select that model. Now,
I'm going to just zoom in. On this
platform, when you select the model, it
has all the details, which is pretty
neat. Also, I think the pricing is
pretty reasonable. So, let's start
asking it a very simple question. Hey,
can you tell me about yourself and who
created you? Okay, this is a
transcription app that I'm currently
working on which is going to be
available pretty soon. Okay, so let's
send this in. So the model is called
theta. You can see the token generation
right now is pretty fast and I think
being ane also contributes a lot to it.
Okay, so here's the response. I am a
large language model developed by ant
group named bailing. I think that's
probably the name of the ant group,
right? And then it goes on to talk about
itself. It says I don't have personal
experiences or consciousness but I can
draw from patterns in data and provide
helpful accurate and context aware
responses. And then it talks about ad
group. It's actually interesting to see
that it tries to explain billing. That's
probably a Chinese word which reflects
values like inclusivity, technological
agility and precise intent
understanding. Very interesting. So, let
me show you some quick tests that I ran.
So, here I asked it to create a 3D
visualization of Los Angeles. The user
should be able to pick a spot on the map
and then it needs to have this fly over
effect. And I wanted everything to be in
the browser. Now, here's the V1. The map
is working properly, but I don't really
see different places that would be of
interest to tourists. After a couple of
iterations, here's what it came up with.
It highlighted a few interesting places.
So, for example, if you click on
downtown LA skyline, it takes us there,
right? Let's say if you click on
Griffith Observatory, it zooms out, then
zooms in on that place. Now, let's check
out Venice Beach Boardwalk. Although, I
think it got the location wrong. So,
pretty neat for the first iteration.
Next, I wanted to test its capabilities
to create websites. So, here's a simple
Pokemon encyclopedia it came up with,
right? So, you can actually click on
different cards. It shows you all the
details. Also, I think it has the
ability to filter out things, right?
Pretty neat for a good coding model.
Now, another test that I usually run is
to see whether the model has been
overfitted on some of these benchmarks
or not that people run. So here's an
example of spinning hexagon, but instead
of hexagon, we have heptagon with 20
balls and very specific details. It came
up with the initial iteration, but it
wasn't really actually showing up
anything. So my followup was that I
don't really see anything. I just see a
blank screen and then it fixed
everything. So here's that version where
it actually follows the instructions
that I provided. And then we also added
another version where you can restart
the simulation if you want. You can
control the rotation of the hap he h he
h he h he h he h he h he h he h he h he
haptagon which is pretty neat. Next I
wanted to see it reasoning capabilities.
So here is the prompt that I usually use
with reasoning models but since this has
the evolutionary chain of thought in its
training. So I wanted to see what's
going to happen. So this is the
classical trolley problem but right now
we have five dead people and there is
one living person who is tied up. Okay.
So it actually doesn't capture that the
five people are already dead. It goes
through the normal response you would
see but at the end it does something
interesting. So in the final answer it
says yes I would pull the lever but I
would do it with profound discomfort not
because one life is worth less than five
but because ethics forces us into tragic
trade-offs where no option is clean.
This dilemma reveals how our moral
framework fractures under impossible
scenarios. This is really profound. I
don't think I have seen anything like
this from a large language model. Now,
for some of my other misguided attention
tests, it has very similar failure cases
to the other models. For example, here's
a variation of wolf, goat, and cabbage
problem. I only want to take the goat to
the other side. But if you look, here's
how it starts. So first we need to take
the good across which is the only step
that we need but then it tries to follow
all the other steps which are completely
unnecessary.
However, I have seen most of the large
reasoning models also fail at this
specific test. Anyways, it's a very
interesting model especially with the
scaling to a trillion parameters in 8
bit floatingoint precision. If you're
interested, I'm going to put a link to
the platform where you can test it out.
But I'll highly recommend to do it
because it's a very interesting model to
talk to. Anyways, I hope you found this
video useful. Thanks for watching and as
always, see you in the next one.